Bona Brian Siagian

(+62) 822 1929 8128 • bonabriansiagian@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/bonabrian https://bonabrian.com • https://github.com/bonabrian

SUMMARY

Full-stack engineer with 4+ years of experience using a range of Frontend and Backend technologies like Java/Kotlin (Spring), PHP (Laravel), Javascript/Typescript (Vue, React).

Developed scalable applications with specifications and business requirements. Perform technical analysis and testing to deliver business value through quality software.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Engineer at Investree

November 2022 - Present

- Followed Agile methodology for application development process.
- Mainly working in Kotlin (Spring) for Back-end and PHP (Laravel) for Legacy and Javascript (Vue) for Frontend.
- Work with Product Managers, QA, and other developer team members to plan new features or tech enhancements.
- Built configurable automation process to improve business operations using RabbitMQ that eliminates 132 clicks per loan process, eliminating 49 manual data input.
- Perform unit tests for every new feature and enhancement. Coverage must be more than 80% both frontend and backend.
- Centralized structured logging to provide monitoring, auditability, business metrics and service metrics (Elastic Search, New Relic).
- Continuous integration and delivery with Jenkins and Git.
- Move storage into proper and more secure (Alibaba).
- Help establish technical standards and best practices.
- Responsible for performing code reviews.
- Used Vue.is to provide usable components in Frontend development.
- Integrated with 3rd party services for digital signature, generating documents, and payment system.

Full Stack Engineer at Varnion

June 2018 - August 2020

- Modifying existing software to correct errors, upgrade interfaces, improve performance and write clean code.
- Analyze and restructure the database to normalized data.
- Improved a Telegram bot using PHP (Slim) for network monitoring.
- Implemented elastic search for network monitoring that increases 30% load time and rendered data visually in real time and using Redis for caching.
- Created a company's profile and careers page using Javascript (Vue and React) for Frontend and PHP (Laravel) for CMS.
- Identify and design new features for the company's products.
- Coded an internal application for Human Resources, General Affair to manage data using PHP (Laravel).

Web Developer Internship at PT. Pupuk Kujang

October 2016 - February 2017

- Working with Manager to plan requirements.
- Designed and developed an internal application from scratch to manage employees, events, etc using PHP native in server-side and JQuery, Bootstrap in client-side.

EDUCATION

Universitas Komputer Indonesia, BandungBachelor's of Information Technology

September 2013 - April 2018

SKILLS

- Java, Kotlin, PHP, Javascript, Typescript
- Spring, Laravel, Vue, React, Node.js, JSON, JQuery
- HTML5, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap
- Redis, RabbitMQ, Elastic Search
- Git, Jenkins, Jira, Unit Testing
- Databases, SQL, MySQL, NoSQL
- Agile, Scrum, Continuous Delivery

PROJECTS

Transaxi (Personal Project)

January 2022 - Present

Transaxi is multi vendor marketplace that I created to improve my full stack development skill and I work as full stack engineer

- Architected system and database structure
- Implemented Midtrans Payment Gateway, Rajaongkir, Google Maps API
- Wrote using Laravel for backend (My plan to migrate using Golang) and Vue.js for frontend
- Using RabbitMO for gueue system and Redis for caching

Yummy Bros (https://yummybros.com), Singapore

February 2022 - May 2022

Yummy Bros is an on-demand healthy food delivery service and provides Asian dishes that are healthier, nutritionally transparent, affordable, and tasty.

Working as frontend developer

- Coded Storefront using Next.js, applied SSR (Server-Side Rendering)
- Built Back Office (CMS) using React.js
- Using Bootstrap as styling CSS framework

Wikas (https://wikas.id)

February 2020 - August 2020

Wikas is News Portal like kumparan.com

I develop this application using Laravel, Vue.js, and Bootstrap

Nazar (https://nazar.id)

October 2019 - February 2020

Nazar is a multi vendor ecommerce store.

I work as Android developer

- Developed using Kotlin
- Using Retrofit to communicate with API
- Integrated with 3rd party services like Google Maps, Espay, Rajaongkir

More projects can be found on

bonabrian.com/work

LANGUAGES

- Bahasa Indonesia
- English